export var reading2Questions = {
    1: {
        id: 'reading2-1',
        headingQuestion: `
            If you enjoy water sports. Hawaii is the place for you. You can go swimming all year round in the warm
            water. You can also try some other water sports that are especially popular in Hawaii: surfing, snorkeling and
            scuba diving. <br>
            Surfing is a sport which started in Hawaii many years ago. In the native Hawaiian language. It means “to
            stick on a wave”. If you want to try surfing, you need to be a good swimmer with an excellent sense of balance. <br>
            Scuba diving and snokerling are 2 ways to get close look at the beauty lying below the surf the ocean. The
            waters of the Hawaiian Islands are clean, clear and warm. They contain hundreds of kinds of colourful fish.
            Scuba diving allows you to see the most interesting undersea sights. “Scuba” means equipment for breathing
            and swimming for under water. If you are adventurous, you might try snokerling instead of scuba diving. Less
            equipment is needed, just a face mask, a breathing tube (snorkel) and flippers for your feet. It only takes a few
            minutes to learn how to snorkel.
 
        `,
        mcQuestions: {
            1: {
                question: `This passage is about _____.`,
                answers: [
                    `Water sports in Hawaii`,
                    `Swimming in Hawaii`,
                    `Surfing in Hawaii`,
                    `Scuba diving in Hawaii`
                ],
                explain: `
                    Kiến thức: Đọc hiểu <br>
                    Giải thích: Đoạn văn này nói về _____. <br>
                    Swimming in Hawaii: Bơi lội ở Hawaii <br>
                    Surfing in Hawaii: Lướt sóng ở Hawaii <br>
                    Scuba diving in Hawaii: Lặn biển ở Hawaii <br>
                    Water sports in Hawaii: Thể thao dưới nước ở Hawaii
                `
            },

            2: {
                question: `It can be inferred from the passage that _____.`,
                answers: [
                    `it is easy to find a way to enjoy water sports in Hawaii`,
                    `all water sports in Hawaii are expensive`,
                    `you need to take a course for all water sports in Hawaii`,
                    `swimming in Hawaii is dangerous`
                ],
                explain: `
                    Kiến thức: Đọc hiểu <br>
                    Giải thích: Có thể suy ra từ đoạn văn rằng _____. <br>
                    Tất cả các môn thể thao dưới nước ở Hawaii đều đắt đỏ. <br>
                    Bạn cần tham gia một khóa học về tất cả các môn thể thao dưới nước ở Hawaii. <br>
                    Bơi ở Hawaii rất nguy hiểm. <br>
                    Thật dễ dàng để tìm cách thưởng thức các môn thể thao dưới nước ở Hawaii.

                `
            },

            3: {
                question: `According to the passage, surfing _____.`,
                answers: [
                    `began in Hawaii many years ago`,
                    `is very dangerous `,
                    `requires expensive equipment`,
                    `does not require a sense of balance`
                ],
                explain: `
                    Kiến thức: Đọc hiểu <br>
                    Giải thích: Theo đoạn văn, lướt sóng _____. <br>
                    is very dangerous: rất nguy hiểm <br>
                    began in Hawaii many years ago: bắt đầu ở Hawaii nhiều năm trước <br>
                    requires expensive equipent: yêu cầu thiết bị đắt tiền <br>
                    does not require a sense of balance: không yêu cầu cảm giác cân bằng <br>
                    Thông tin: Surfing is a sport which started in Hawaii many years ago. <br>
                    Tạm dịch: Lướt sóng là một môn thể thao bắt đầu ở Hawaii từ nhiều năm trước
                `
            },

            4: {
                question: `The waters of the Hawaii Islands are _____.`,
                answers: [
                    `clean, clear and warm`,
                    `often quite cold`,
                    `usually very dark`,
                    `full of dangerous fish`
                ],
                explain: `
                    Kiến thức: Đọc hiểu <br>
                    Giải thích: Vùng biển của Quần đảo Hawaii là _____. <br>
                    often quite cold: thường khá lạnh <br>
                    clean, clear and warm: sạch sẽ, trong lành và ấm áp <br>
                    usually very dark: thường rất tối <br>
                    full of dangerous fish: đầy cá nguy hiểm <br>
                    Thông tin: The waters of the Hawaiian Islands are clean, clear and warm. <br>
                    Tạm dịch: Vùng biển của Quần đảo Hawaii sạch, trong và ấm áp.
                `
            },

            5: {
                question: `All of the following equipment is needed for snokerling EXCEPT _____.`,
                answers: [
                    `surfboard`,
                    `a race mask`,
                    `flippers`,
                    `a breathing tube`
                ],
                explain: `
                    Kiến thức: Đọc hiểu <br>
                    Giải thích: Tất cả các thiết bị sau đây đều cần thiết để lặn với ống thở NGOẠI TRỪ _____. <br>
                    surfboard: ván lướt sóng <br>
                    a race mask: mặt nạ đua <br>
                    flippers: chân chèo <br>
                    a breathing tube: ống thở <br>
                    Thông tin: If you are adventurous, you might try snorkeling instead of scuba diving. Less equipment is
                    needed, just a face mask, a breathing tube (snorkel) and flippers for your feet. <br>
                    Tạm dịch: . Nếu bạn là người thích phiêu lưu, bạn có thể thử lặn với ống thở thay vì lặn biển. Cần ít thiết bị
                    hơn, chỉ cần mặt nạ, ống thở (ống thở) và chân chèo
                `
            },
        }
    },
    2: {
        id: 'reading2-2',
        headingQuestion: `
            The Amazon Rainforest is the largest tropical rainforest in the world. It covers more than five million 
            square kilometers and is located in South America. The forest is home to millions of species of insects, 
            plants, birds, and other forms of life. <br>
            The Amazon River, which runs through the forest, is the second longest river in the world. The rainforest 
            is often called the "lungs of the planet" because its trees absorb huge amounts of carbon dioxide and 
            release oxygen. However, the forest is disappearing at an alarming rate due to deforestation for farming 
            and logging. If this continues, it will have a serious impact on the world's climate.
        `,
        mcQuestions: {
            1: {
                question: `Where is the Amazon Rainforest located?`,
                answers: [`In South America`, `In North America`, `In Africa`, `In Asia`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...and is located in South America."`
            },
            2: {
                question: `Why is it called the "lungs of the planet"?`,
                answers: [`Because it releases oxygen`, `Because it is very large`, `Because it has many rivers`, `Because it is green`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...absorb huge amounts of carbon dioxide and release oxygen."`
            },
            3: {
                question: `The Amazon River is _____.`,
                answers: [`the second longest river`, `the longest river`, `the shortest river`, `the widest river`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...is the second longest river in the world."`
            },
            4: {
                question: `What is the main cause of the forest's disappearance?`,
                answers: [`Deforestation`, `Flooding`, `Overpopulation`, `Forest fires`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...due to deforestation for farming and logging."`
            },
            5: {
                question: `What will happen if the forest continues to disappear?`,
                answers: [`Impact on world's climate`, `More insects will grow`, `The river will dry up`, `Farming will be easier`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...it will have a serious impact on the world's climate."`
            }
        }
    },
    3: {
        id: 'reading2-3',
        headingQuestion: `
            Alexander Graham Bell was born in Scotland in 1847. He was a scientist, inventor, and engineer. 
            He is best known for inventing the first practical telephone. Bell's father and grandfather 
            worked with people who were deaf, which inspired him to study sound and communication. <br>
            In 1876, at the age of 29, Bell was granted a patent for his invention of the telephone. He 
            famously said the first words over the phone to his assistant, Thomas Watson: "Mr. Watson, 
            come here, I want to see you." Besides the telephone, Bell also worked on other inventions, 
            including a metal detector and flying machines. He died in Canada in 1922.
        `,
        mcQuestions: {
            1: {
                question: `What was Alexander Graham Bell's most famous invention?`,
                answers: [`The telephone`, `The metal detector`, `The radio`, `The computer`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...best known for inventing the first practical telephone."`
            },
            2: {
                question: `Bell was born in _____.`,
                answers: [`Scotland`, `Canada`, `America`, `England`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "Alexander Graham Bell was born in Scotland..."`
            },
            3: {
                question: `What inspired Bell to study sound and communication?`,
                answers: [`His family's work with the deaf`, `His teachers`, `His love for music`, `His friends`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "Bell's father and grandfather worked with people who were deaf..."`
            },
            4: {
                question: `How old was Bell when he got the patent for the telephone?`,
                answers: [`29`, `47`, `22`, `35`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "In 1876, at the age of 29, Bell was granted a patent..."`
            },
            5: {
                question: `Who was Thomas Watson?`,
                answers: [`Bell's assistant`, `Bell's father`, `A deaf person`, `A scientist`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...to his assistant, Thomas Watson..."`
            }
        }
    },
    4: {
        id: 'reading2-4',
        headingQuestion: `
            Solar energy is the heat and light that comes from the sun. It is a renewable source of energy, 
            which means it will never run out. Many people use solar panels on their roofs to collect sunlight 
            and turn it into electricity. <br>
            Solar energy is good for the environment because it does not produce pollution or greenhouse 
            gases like coal or oil do. It is also becoming cheaper as technology improves. However, there 
            are some problems. For example, solar panels cannot produce electricity at night, and they 
            are less effective when it is cloudy or rainy. Scientists are working on better batteries 
            to store solar energy for use when the sun is not shining.
        `,
        mcQuestions: {
            1: {
                question: `Solar energy is a _____ source of energy.`,
                answers: [`renewable`, `non-renewable`, `limited`, `polluted`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "It is a renewable source of energy..."`
            },
            2: {
                question: `What do solar panels do?`,
                answers: [`Turn sunlight into electricity`, `Heat the water`, `Make the house dark`, `Clean the roof`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...collect sunlight and turn it into electricity."`
            },
            3: {
                question: `Why is solar energy good for the environment?`,
                answers: [`It doesn't produce pollution`, `It is expensive`, `It is very bright`, `It makes no noise`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...it does not produce pollution or greenhouse gases..."`
            },
            4: {
                question: `When can solar panels NOT produce electricity?`,
                answers: [`At night`, `In the morning`, `In the afternoon`, `On sunny days`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...solar panels cannot produce electricity at night..."`
            },
            5: {
                question: `What are scientists working on to improve solar use?`,
                answers: [`Better batteries`, `More sun`, `Bigger roofs`, `Stronger light`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...working on better batteries to store solar energy..."`
            }
        }
    },
    5: {
        id: 'reading2-5',
        headingQuestion: `
            Mount Everest is the highest mountain in the world. It is located in the Himalayas, on the 
            border between Nepal and China. The mountain is 8,848 meters high. Every year, hundreds 
            of climbers try to reach the summit. <br>
            Climbing Everest is very dangerous. The air is very thin at the top, making it hard to breathe. 
            The weather can also change quickly, with strong winds and freezing temperatures. The first 
            people to reach the summit were Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay in 1953. Since then, 
            many people have made the climb, but it remains one of the greatest challenges for any athlete.
        `,
        mcQuestions: {
            1: {
                question: `How high is Mount Everest?`,
                answers: [`8,848 meters`, `1,953 meters`, `5,000 meters`, `10,000 meters`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "The mountain is 8,848 meters high."`
            },
            2: {
                question: `In which mountain range is Everest located?`,
                answers: [`The Himalayas`, `The Alps`, `The Andes`, `The Rockies`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "It is located in the Himalayas..."`
            },
            3: {
                question: `Why is it hard to breathe at the top of Everest?`,
                answers: [`The air is thin`, `It is too cold`, `It is too windy`, `There are no trees`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "The air is very thin at the top, making it hard to breathe."`
            },
            4: {
                question: `Who were the first people to reach the summit?`,
                answers: [`Hillary and Norgay`, `Bell and Watson`, `Smith and Jones`, `Neil Armstrong`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...were Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay in 1953."`
            },
            5: {
                question: `Mount Everest is on the border of Nepal and _____.`,
                answers: [`China`, `India`, `Vietnam`, `Thailand`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...on the border between Nepal and China."`
            }
        }
    },
    6: {
        id: 'reading2-6',
        headingQuestion: `
            The Olympic Games are the world's leading international sporting event. They happen 
            every four years, with Summer and Winter Games. The first modern Olympics took 
            place in Athens, Greece, in 1896. <br>
            Thousands of athletes from more than 200 nations participate in various sports. 
            The goal of the Olympics is to bring people from different countries together 
            in peace. The five rings on the Olympic flag represent the five major continents 
            of the world: Africa, the Americas, Asia, Europe, and Oceania. Winning a gold 
            medal is the highest honor for any Olympic athlete.
        `,
        mcQuestions: {
            1: {
                question: `How often do the Olympic Games happen?`,
                answers: [`Every four years`, `Every two years`, `Every year`, `Every five years`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "They happen every four years..."`
            },
            2: {
                question: `Where were the first modern Olympics held?`,
                answers: [`Athens, Greece`, `London, UK`, `Paris, France`, `Tokyo, Japan`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...took place in Athens, Greece, in 1896."`
            },
            3: {
                question: `How many nations participate in the Olympics?`,
                answers: [`More than 200`, `Exactly 100`, `Less than 50`, `About 500`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...from more than 200 nations participate..."`
            },
            4: {
                question: `What do the five rings represent?`,
                answers: [`Five continents`, `Five countries`, `Five sports`, `Five medals`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "...represent the five major continents of the world..."`
            },
            5: {
                question: `What is the highest honor for an Olympic athlete?`,
                answers: [`Winning a gold medal`, `Wearing the uniform`, `Meeting the president`, `Travel to Greece`],
                explain: `Thông tin: "Winning a gold medal is the highest honor..."`
            }
        }
    }
}